<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on Asa Needle&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://asaneedle.com/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on Asa Needle&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {2020}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 13:50:13 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asaneedle.com/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Night of the Hunter</title>
      <link>https://asaneedle.com/writing/the-night-of-the-hunter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 13:50:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asaneedle.com/writing/the-night-of-the-hunter/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I had a strong reaction to my Pfizer booster shot. It knocked me out for the entire day, but I was finally able to eat a banana and a few saltines by evening. I took the time to finish watching The Night of the Hunter, the noir classic directed by Charles Laughton (his only film as director) and starring Robert Mitchum as a charlatan priest and murderer. It reminded me forcefully of Bergman&amp;rsquo;s Fanny and Alexander: both films feature a preacher who marries a single mother with two children, and is gradually revealed to be psychopathic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harold Bloom&#39;s The American Religion</title>
      <link>https://asaneedle.com/writing/bloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 10:23:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asaneedle.com/writing/bloom/</guid>
      <description>Harold Bloom is always an entertaining writer, in a curmudgeonly, opinionated way. Specifically, I think he&amp;rsquo;s immensely talented at &amp;ldquo;appreciative&amp;rdquo; writing, criticism that tries to express something of the gestalt or aesthetic power of the work being criticized. He writes wonderfully about Shakespeare and Dickinson for example. It&amp;rsquo;s something akin to what Sontag talks about in her essay Against Interpretation. It&amp;rsquo;s also a reason why I like Ebert&amp;rsquo;s film reviews; the love of movies just shines through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching myself to read a book in French</title>
      <link>https://asaneedle.com/writing/french/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 08:53:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asaneedle.com/writing/french/</guid>
      <description>I thought today I&amp;rsquo;d write up my journey in learning French so far, with some notes at the end about where I want to go from here.
It started on a whim. My partner speaks French and I wanted to be able to surprise her by knowing a few basic phrases in French. I was also feeling burnt out on Spanish, which I had done in college, and had been picking up intermittently since then, never with much success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fifth Season</title>
      <link>https://asaneedle.com/writing/fifth-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 10:50:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asaneedle.com/writing/fifth-season/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading N.K. Jemisin&amp;rsquo;s The Fifth Season and had blast. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve been immersed in a fiction book. Sometimes the writing and dialogue made my eyes roll, but that comes with the territory somewhat in YA/science fiction. It&amp;rsquo;s the world-building and plotting that keeps you hooked. There&amp;rsquo;s lots of interesting things going on with race and gender. There are trans characters, and the world of the Fifth Season is one where hierarchies based on racial phenotype coexist with hierarchies based on whether or not you can earth-bend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Curiosity Journal</title>
      <link>https://asaneedle.com/writing/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:37:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asaneedle.com/writing/first-post/</guid>
      <description>My new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution is to write every day. To that end, I&amp;rsquo;m starting a curiosity journal, and for now housing it here on my personal site. What&amp;rsquo;s a curiosity journal? Well, it&amp;rsquo;s a practice I first encountered while taking a course called The Ethics of Curiosity with Perry Zurn (who as of last year has a book out all about of curiosity). He told us to take notes on how curiosity showed up in our lives, which could include the feeling in ourselves, what it was directed towards, and even how we might see the word used in the wider world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
